## J. BLAKE DENOUDEN

Wichita, KS 316.227.7942 | denoudenjb@yahoo.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Administrator, Personnel Manager, and Military Veteran with 5+ years of business acumen, proven experience creating and implementing clear organizational vision and continuous process improvement. Exceptional consensus builder and crossfunctional leader with a background in Ethical Leadership, Finance and Budgeting, Program Management, Business Development, and Corporate Compliance with state, federal, and military regulations. Implemented risk management measures to manage an \$500K+ program and annual operating budgets of over \$40K. Adept at translating strategic goals into achievable team tasks, conflict resolution, customer relationship management, organizational development and analyzing organizational needs. Career supported by a Master of Science in Innovation Design and a Bachelor of Business Administration with emphasis in Management.

- Leadership
- Data Management
- Data Analysis | Metrics
- Organizational Development
- Program | Project Management
- Policy Implementation
- Planning | Execution
- Budget Analysis | Forecasting
- Resource Allocation

#### **KEY HIGHLIGHTS**

**Leadership:** Proven track record for leading multi-dimensional teams in high pressure, high tempo environments producing on schedule and within required deliverables.

**Relationship Building:** Leadership, management, oral and written communication, and interpersonal skills. Thrive in both independent and collaborative work environments. Skilled at developing and cultivating key relationships and establishing effective collaborations.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Department of Defense | McConnell AFB, KS Program Coordinator

Oct. 2020 - Present

Served as primary administrator for applicable regulations, human resources, finance, production, logistics, and fiscal law issues. Oversaw and coordinated the operational aspects of various projects. Served as a liaison between project management and the project team, planning, engineering, line management, and the customer on issues such as operational and scheduling concerns.

- Performed organization structure, workforce utilization, and space utilization for procedural and relationship aspects
  of the organization, improving the efficiency of internal administrative operations for upwards of 200 personnel in 7
  different departments
- Maintained security of classified and sensitive information required for mission performance and forecasted resource and equipment needs to ensure unit was operationally ready; identified best practices, led continuous improvement initiatives to raise safety awareness, and improved safe operating practices
- Met strategic business needs by being involved in cross-functional teams offering accurate analysis; provided timely responses for various problems related to data safety and compliance HIPAA/FOIA
- Utilized an effective Composite Risk Management process to identify and analyze risk while developing mitigation measures that decreased the likelihood of accidents or safety incidents during operation

# United States Air Force | McConnell AFB, KS

Mar. 2017 – Present

# Operations Manager, Administration and Personnel

Managed and provided daily event and task coordination to all senior full-time staff with direct support of 200+ personnel supporting the creation and implementation of logistics, maintenance, and analysis reports.

- Developed and maintained relationships with internal and external stakeholders and staff members to ensure the success of business development initiatives maintained an 83% operational readiness rate for over 200 military employees which was better than 90% of comparable departments
- Functioned as the chief advisor to all executive, senior, and mid-level leaders on all matters, including kinetic activities, military discipline actions, fiscal and training issues, etc.; ensured all executive leaders had access to all relevant legal implications
- Wrote and presented operations plans for internal and external agencies to rapidly refit, train, and integrate new
  personnel for an organization of 800 employees; functioned as the primary point of contact and liaison with state
  and federal government officials

• Ensured department officials complied with state laws, regulations, contracting, budgetary, fiscal, personnel, and reporting requirements

J. BLAKE DENOUDEN, PG. 2

#### **Unit Administrator**

Enforced compliance with organizational programs such as scheduled inventories, safety reports, awards, promotions, and separations. Oversaw personnel schedules, prioritizing urgent department, and establishing daily, weekly, and monthly task plans.

- Planned, programmed, documented, executed, coordinated, and analyzed fiscal, manpower, doctrine, instruction and
  equipment requirements in support of operational initiatives; provided sound advice and recommendations as to
  appropriate strategies, priorities, resource requirements, and resource allocations needed to accomplish objectives
- Reviewed status of projects to ensure timelines were on time and within budget; assessed project issues and developed solutions to meet production, quality and customer-satisfaction goals and objectives
- Provided guidance to leadership in planning and developed capital improvement and short- and long-range plans;
   facilitated communication within the department, ensuring implementation of procedures for standard delivery of services
- Identified the need for special projects and initiated milestones and goals; ensured participation and outcomes of special projects resulted in positive impact on the command and improved quality
- Provided technical oversight for programs associated with business processes, resource management, organizational
  analysis, systems management, strategic planning and leadership; initiated appropriate courses of action, priorities,
  resource requirements, and equipment and personnel allocations necessary to accomplish organizational objectives

# Marriott International | Wichita, KS Sales and Reservations

Jan. 2017 – Oct. 2020

Coordinated with staff members to client-focused training plans, ensuring teaching functions were processed into the correct support systems and software programs aimed at capturing, detailing, and compiling information supporting over 3,000 patrons. Drove lateral company-wide communication and collaboration through employee engagement, update meetings, and client satisfaction surveys.

- Utilized internal software to account for training and operations enhancements, procurement, and proposals through automated reporting, to maximize efficiency within financial constraints
- Mentored 15 employees through policy change, schedules, and training planning; contributed to staff development
  and operations of supply support data systems, equipment review, supply procedure, budget adjustment, and policy
  change
- Received calls, greeted visitors, and answer requests for information using knowledge of the organization and property; used point-of-sale systems to generate and process payments and manage reward-accounts and point balances
- Built rapport with the customer by understanding their needs and providing advice to fit their itinerary needs
- Advised management and leadership on policy and program matters, making or recommending appropriate action plans
- Provided sales trends and reports to ensure cost, service, and products were compliant with agreed upon orders
- Followed procedures for managing the purchase of needed facility goods, replacement items, incomplete orders, shortages, and credit arrangements

### **EDUCATION | TRAINING**

Master of Science | Innovation Design | Wichita State University | In Progress; Fall 2023 Expected Bachelor of Business Administration | Management | Thomas Edison State University | 2018 Advanced Leadership and Professional Development School | United States Air Force Personnel Management School and Certification Program | United States Air Force

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Project Officer (CPO) | DOHL Notary Public | State of Kansas Six Sigma Green Belt | CCSC **Software**: Microsoft Office Business Suite, Windows 2000, XP, Server 2000/2003, OpenXPath **Operating Systems**: Mac / Microsoft Windows